Hello everyone and welcome
to EnglishPod, my name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and
today we've got another
episode in our series
about giving a presentation.
That's right today
we're going to talk about
some key elements of the
topic that we're talking about.
We're talking about a laptop computer so
we're going to give some more details and
characteristics about the computer
and what makes it so special.
So let's take a listen to
what Mr. Ford has to say
about what makes this
company's computers very special.
Now a key question
you might ask yourself is
what differentiates
the new X420 line with
our previous models and also of
course with some of our competitors.
In other words what makes the
X420 stand out from all the others?
This is a key question and it's something
I'd like to explore in a little depth.
Firstly the X420 has a range of USPs
that really make it a cut above the rest.
The first thing to
mention is that the X420 is
the first and a new generation
of ultra-light laptop computers.
It is only two pounds which compares very
favorably with all our key competitors.
In terms of computer performance for
such a light machine it's very powerful.
Four gigabytes of RAM
with an ultra-fast processor.
The most advanced video
and sound cards on the
market are installed with a
crystal clear 15-inch LCD display.
The X420 really stands out
as next-generation laptop.
Compared with our previous X540
range it really is in a league of its own.
Now if we go on to look at projected sales
for the X420 we can see that sales revenue
for 2010 is expected to
hit at least $20 million.
Now this is really a conservative estimate.
If our marketing
campaign is successful I'm
confident that we can see a
doubling of this figure at the very least.
Now please bear in mind that this
is only for the first year production.
I'm certain that in the
coming three years the
X420 will actually overtake
all our existing products.
Both in terms of sales and revenue.
Okay, now let's move
on to discuss our
marketing concept and
look more closely at our
key competitors.
We're back so we obviously
heard a lot of vocab
here, a lot of interesting
things regarding the computer.
Why don't we take a look at some of the
words that he used on language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
So the first word that is pretty
challenging is to differentiate it's a verb.
Mr. Ford says ask
yourself what it is that
differentiates this new
computer line with other ones.
That's right.
So to differentiate that
means what makes it different?
What is so special about it, right?
That's right.
So you can ask a question like this.
What differentiates Apple
computers from other computers?
That's right.
So you're asking what
makes it so different?
That's right.
So then he rephrases
the question and he says,
well, in other words, what makes the X420
stand out from all the other computers?
All right.
So this is a verbal phrase to stand out.
It's very similar to the one that
we just mentioned to differentiate.
This means what makes
this computer special?
Why is it unique?
That's right.
So we're basically saying why is this
one more noticeable than the rest?
That's to stand out.
So maybe if everyone
in the office is wearing
white t-shirts today,
but somebody comes in
wearing a red t-shirt, that
person is going to stand out.
Actually, Marco, I
think today that's even
more wearing a red t-shirt
today, so you stand out.
Okay.
So now as he continued
to talk about the
computer, he used this
prefix before in adjective.
That was very interesting.
He said, this computer is ultra light
and then he said it's ultra thin as well.
That it has an ultra fast processor.
Okay.
So ultra light, ultra fast ultra thin,
this is a way of saying very, very.
That's right.
So that's what he's saying.
He's saying it's very light.
It's very thin.
So that's pretty much the structure.
You can add ultra before in adjective
to emphasize that it's very something.
That's right.
So when I think of cool
actors, I think of James Dean.
He was ultra cool.
Ultra cool.
Very cool.
That's right.
Okay.
So you can do it with
pretty much all adjectives,
but you can't really exaggerate
and use it all the time.
That's what well, the key is to
remember this is an exaggeration.
So yeah, you don't
want to use it all the time.
But if you want to make
sure you say that something
is, if you want to
emphasize that something
is special or that it's very, very
something, you use the word ultra.
That's right.
Okay.
As you continue to talk
about the characteristics
of the laptop computer,
he made reference
to the LCD display, the
screen of the computer.
And he said that it's a crystal
clear 15 inch LCD display.
What does he mean by crystal clear?
Well, crystal is a very
special kind of glass, right?
And so it's expensive.
It's what some people
have as their special
glassware, you know, wine
glasses and drinking glasses.
And so crystal is very special because
it's so, it's so clear to see through.
So transparent.
It's transparent.
Light goes through it.
You can see everything.
Everything is crystal clear is
to say that it's very, very clear.
It's extremely clear.
It says clear as crystal.
Okay.
So basically the
screen of this computer,
you can see very, very well
everything that's on the screen.
Everything that's happening.
All the colors, all of the words, okay.
And then moving away
from the characteristics
of the computer, he talked about projected
sales and he expected $20 million.
And he said that that is a
very conservative estimate.
Okay.
So an estimate is like a guess.
It's how much we think we will earn in a
year or how much we think will happen.
But in this case, a conservative
estimate means that it's a low estimate.
You know, we might
make $20 million next year.
That's conservative.
Another estimate is
we will make $40 million.
So that's not conservative.
That's right.
Okay.
So as you said, an estimate is we are
more or less guessing how much it would be.
And conservative.
So what would, what would be the
opposite of a conservative estimate?
You could say a generous estimate,
that means you're giving a lot.
Okay.
So a generous estimate is our revenues
will be at around $60 million next year.
Okay.
Very good.
So I think we've taken in a lot.
Why don't we take a break?
Let's listen to the dialogue again.
And we'll be back with Fluency Builder.
Now, a key question
you might ask yourself
is what differentiates
the new X420 line with
our previous models and also of
course with some of our competitors.
In other words, what makes the
X420 stand out from all the others?
This is a key question and it's something
I'd like to explore in a little depth.
Firstly, the X420 has a range of USPs
that really make it a cut above the rest.
The first thing to
mention is that the X420 is
the first and a new generation
of ultra-light laptop computers.
It is only two pounds, which compares very
favorably with all our key competitors.
In terms of computer performance for
such a light machine, it's very powerful.
Four gigabytes of RAM
with an ultra-fast processor.
The most advanced
video and sound cards on
the market are installed with a
crystal-clear 15-inch LCD display.
The X420 really stands
out as next generation
laptop, compared with our previous X540
range it really is in a league of its own.
Now, if we go on to look at projected sales
for the X420, we can see that sales revenue
for 2010 is expected to
hit at least $20 million.
Now this is really a conservative estimate.
If our marketing campaign is
successful, I'm confident that
we can see a doubling of
this figure at the very least.
Now please bear in mind that this is
only for the first year of production.
I'm certain that in the coming three years,
the X420 will actually overtake all our
existing products, both in
terms of sales and revenue.
Okay, now let's move
on to discuss our
marketing concept and look
more closely at our key competitors.
All right, we're back with Fluency Builder.
Let's take a look at some key phrases now.
Fluency Builder.
All right, so our first
phrase is a very important
phrase when you're trying to
differentiate different products or things.
We say this is really a cut above the rest.
Okay, so if something
is a cut above the rest,
it means that it's in a different
category from everyone else.
It's a lot better.
It is a lot better.
So you can say that we
saw many, many applicants
who wanted to come for a job at our company,
and John, he was a cut above the rest.
He was much better than
all of the other candidates.
Okay, very good.
So a cut above the rest.
Now when we talked
about this computer, he
also made reference saying that,
you know, it's in a league of its own.
The computer is so
powerful, it's so new,
it's so fantastic that it's
in a league of its own.
Okay, so a league is like
a category in this case.
We have good computers, we have great
computers, but this computer is so good.
It's in an entirely new category.
It's awesome.
It's amazing.
It's mind blowing.
So we often say this with
new things, you know,
this is great, but nothing
before it can compare.
They're just not as good.
So it's in a league of its own.
Okay, very good.
So you can make reference to
products or also people, right?
A person can be in a league of his own.
That's right.
So, you know, there are a lot
of good singers in the world.
But this singer, he is
in a league of his own.
Oh, okay, very good.
And to finish off Louis Biller towards the
end of his dialogue, he said to please bear
in mind that this is only
the first year of production.
Okay, so we're talking
about making these products,
you know, there's going
to take time to make money.
And Mr. Ford would like us to bear something
in mind, to bear in mind this fact.
So to bear something in mind
means to remember or to consider.
Okay.
So he's asking us to please consider that
it's only the first year of production.
So we can't really expect too much.
That's right.
So you could say this about
a number of different things.
I could say, you know,
Marco, here's, here's my report.
Please look over it.
Please bear in mind.
This is only a first draft.
Okay.
So I will make some edits.
I will make some changes.
It's not perfect.
And I know that.
So please bear this in mind.
Okay.
So you're kind of warning me.
You're kind of letting
me know to consider the
fact that it's not the final report
and there might be some mistakes.
Exactly.
So to bear in mind that this saying this is
kind of like a warning that things are not
perfect yet, but, you know,
I still want your opinion.
Okay.
Very good.
So why don't we listen to the
dialogue again and we'll be back in a bit.
Now a key question
you might ask yourself is
what differentiates the new
X420 line with our previous models.
And also of course with
some of our competitors.
In other words, what makes the
X420 stand out from all the others?
This is a key question and it's something
I'd like to explore in a little depth.
Firstly the X420 has a range of USPs
that really make it a cut above the rest.
The first thing to mention
is that the X420 is the first
and a new generation of
ultra light laptop computers.
It is only two pounds, which compares very
favorably with all our key competitors.
In terms of computer performance, for
such a light machine, it's very powerful.
For gigabytes of
RAM with an ultra fast
processor, the most advanced
video and sound cards
on the market are installed with
a crystal clear 15 inch LCD display.
The X420 really stands
out as next generation
laptop, compared with our previous X540
range it really is in a league of its own.
Now if we go on to look at projected sales
for the X420, we can see that sales revenue
for 2010 is expected to
hit at least 20 million dollars.
Now this is really a conservative estimate.
If our marketing
campaign is successful, I'm
confident that we could see a
doubling of this figure at the very least.
Now please bear in mind that this
is only for the first year production.
I'm certain that in the coming three years,
the X420 will actually overtake all our
existing products, both in
terms of sales and revenue.
Okay, now let's move
on to discuss our
marketing concept and
look more closely at our
key competitors.
We're back.
You've probably saw this acronym in the
very first part of the dialogue when he said
that the X420 has a range of USPs
that really make it a cut above the rest.
All right, so this is a
very special acronym
for the business
world and it stands for
you unique S selling and P
point, unique selling point.
That's right.
So as the name says, a unique selling point
are characteristics that are unique to the
machine that allow it
to be more competitive
and to persuade people
to buy it or to sell itself.
All right, so the new iPhone has a
very interesting unique selling point.
It has two cameras, one on
the front and one on the back.
So that really differentiates it
from other phones on the market.
That's right.
So that is what a USP is
or a unique selling point.
As we said, it's an
acronym in the business
world, but next time that
you find the opportunity
to use it, I'm sure it's
going to sound amazing.
Yes, very professional
USP unique selling point.
All right, so that's all the time we have.
Be sure to check out the next
part of our series next week.
And of course, if you
have any questions or
comments, you're always
welcome at EnglishPod.com.
We will see you there.
Bye.